CHEK HOI, NICOLA WONG

Bsc Computer Science



Ipswich, UK | North Point, HK



wongchekhoi@gmail.com



+44 7871607512



/nicola-wong1

REFERENCE AVAILABLE ON REQUEST

</>> TECH STACK

REACTIS IAVA SPRING BOOT HTML / CSS PYTHON REST API PYTORCH DETECTRON2 TENSOFLOW GIT DOCKER CI / CD



WORK EXPERIENCE

2021

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Al Modelling (Contract)

Insight Robotics Science Park, HK

2018-20

RESEARCH SPECIALIST Al Modelling & Resource Optimisation

British Telecoms Plc - Applied Research Adastral Park, Martlesham, UK

2017-18

TRAINEE JAVA DEVELOPER

Full-stack

Bertrams Books / Connect Books Norwich, UK



T EDUCATION

BSC (HONS) COMPUTER SCIENCE 2013-16

Grade: First

/ UNIVERSITY OF EAST ANGLIA, NORWICH. UK

2010-13

HONG KONG DIPLOMA OF SECONDARY EDUCATION Grade: 5*, 5, 4 (~UCAS Tariff 330) / SACRED HEART CANOSSIAN COLLEGE



文A LANGUAGE

- ENGLISH
- · CANTONESE
- MANDARIN



PROFILE

I am a **highly motivated** individual who is always looking for a challenge.

I am also a communicative trilingual, a passionate team player and a confident leader.

I have 4 years of experience in Software Development and am looking for work around the area of Data Science. Open to relocate internationally.



A PROJECTS

OBJECT DETECTION: SATELLITE IMG

2021 - Ongoing | Insight Robotics

Developing AI solutions to detect objects in satellite images - comissioned by Hong Kong Lands Department.

Applied object detection and semantic segmentation algorithms to the problem.

Detectron2 Pixel Manipulation

Pytorch Convolutional Neural Networks

WORKFORCE SIMULATION

2018 - 2020 | BT - Applied Research

Simulated work-schedule of field workers stochastically in telecoms. Accelerated business decisions on workforce allocation

Algorithms-Design Modelling

Discrete-Event Simulation

Spring Boot ReactJS

EV-FLEET TRANSITION

2020 | BT - Applied Research

Sourced and built data models from unstructured fleet and power data across BT. Planned the transition from using traditional fueled vehicles to electrical vehicles in the telecoms industry.

Data Cleaning Data Visualisation

Data Comprehension Web Prototyping

MUSIC GENRE CLASSIFICATION

2021 - Ongoing | Hobby Project

Filtering audio signals and extracting features from data with LPC and MFCC.

Utilising Tensorflow libraries to classify audio data into musical genres using

Long-Short-Term-Memory Neutral Networks.

Tensorflow Audio Signal Processing

Recurrent Neural Networks

WORK ALLOCATION OPTIMISATION

2020 | BT - Applied Research

Researched different famous algorithms. Implemented appropriate solution for the 'Assignment Problem' applied to human-resources problem.

Pitched and deployed by the business.

Hungarian Algorithms Research

3D BALLET SIMULATION APP

End-to-End Business Solution

2016 | Final-year Project at UEA

Created an interactive 3D Ballet Tutorial app which acts as a 'Ballet Dictionary' Technical Ballet terms are illustrated by a motion-capture-animated 3D rig.

Unreal Engine 4 3D Modelling

3DSMax Visual Motion Capture



ACHIEVEMENTS

Pivotal Spring: Core Training Course Completed 2017

Podcast Co-creator

2021 - Ongoing | Silly Conv Valley A Cantonese podcast on Technology and Cultural Lifestyle.

Self-producing and editing bi-weekly episodes. Utilized social platforms to publish and promote the show to engage with the audience.

Audio Editing Broadcasting

Creative Writing Digital Marketing

ISTQB Foundation Tester Certification Acquired 2018

Qualified (Nomad) Coding teacher

2021 - Ongoing | Preface Coding Hosted a 5-day sicence workshop educating

primary students on STEM. One-to-one instruction to teens and adults on programming and Machine Learning

Mentored Research Apprentice 2020 | BT - Applied Research

Gave technical guidance to a degree apprentice in my team on full-stack development.

Education Effective Communication